#### M. CHRISTINA THOMPSON

Portland, OR ♦ (971) 678-6424 ♦ square.one@comcast.net

#### **Profile**

Responsible, self-motivated professional with HR, Supply Chain/Production Planning & Scheduling, Customer Service and Office Administration background. Experienced in a fast-paced manufacturing environment with constantly changing deadlines. Excellent communication, problem solving and analytical skills with proven ability to interact at all levels of an organization. Knowledge of HR policies and procedures and current state/federal employment regulations. Understanding of Continuous Improvement Methodologies. APICS CPIM certification coursework started March 2011.

#### **Skills**

Admin/Clerical Exp. (15+ yrs.) HR Assist/Generalist Exp. (6+ yrs.) Customer Service Exp. (10+ yrs.) Prod. Plan/Scheduling Exp. (2 yrs.) Inventory Control Exp. (2 yrs.) HRIS (AS400) Time Keeping Software (Etime/Kronos) Benefits /Compensation FMLA/OFLA/ADA/EEO/WC Employment Law Personnel File Management Program/Event Coordination HSE Policies Microsoft Office Applications Expense Reporting Travel Arrangements
Calendar Management
Manager/Executive Level Support
Purchase Orders
Customer Order Entry/Mgmt.
Work Order Entry/Mgmt.
Blueprint Reading

## **Experience**

Recruitment

## APICS - Portland Chapter - Portland, OR

Basics of Supply Chain Management, Course Completion Certificate May 2011

## Chapman/Brandman University

• SHRM Essentials of Human Resource Management Certification, May 2010

Portland State University – coursework in Economics and Statistics 2008-2009

#### SAINT-GOBAIN CRYSTALS - Milford, NH

**Production Planning Manager**, 2005 to 2007

While performing planning duties, acted as backup for HR manager as needed and during a prolonged leave of absence. In addition, continued to be responsible for maintaining time keeping system/PTO logs, liaising with corporate payroll and ensuring the accuracy and full legal compliance of all timekeeping and payroll records. Project-managed launch of the Kronos timekeeping system and worked with corporate administrators to program paycodes/payrules (for two locations). Responsible for error checking the "test-run" and training managers and supervisors on the use of the new system. Organized and maintained record retention database and files before facilitating transfer to an offsite vendor.

Reported directly to Facilities manager. Managed all WIP and FG production planning functions during a period of increased growth in sales. Handled large volume of work with many interruptions. Worked to increase on-time delivery and maintained a 99% accuracy rate on quarterly/yearly inventory audits. Utilized 5S process to reorganize the FG, RM, and customer JIT inventory stock rooms. Responsible for the transfer of all RM and FG inventory and corresponding records from a closing out – of-state facility. Streamlined daily production planning meeting which decreased the meeting time and increased the efficiency/accuracy of reported data.

- Directly accountable for accuracy of ERP data (PRMS), WIP and Finished Goods inventory levels, monitored inventory to identify over stocks, stock outs, scrap and obsolete product.
- Coordinated physical inventory/cycle count programs, identified/resolved discrepancies and made necessary data adjustments in the ERP system.
- Conducted daily planning meetings with a cross-functional management team in order to effectively manage and meet customer demand.
- Responsible for communicating critical shortages and customer expedites to production.
- Utilized ERP system to schedule, plan and forecast demand and created/rescheduled/closed all work orders accordingly.
- Worked with engineering and quality departments to maintain BOMs, routings, prints and other related data.

- Worked on a daily basis with RM Planning manager to ensure raw material availability and production capacity
  of growth department; with customer service to ensure on-time delivery of CO's; with shipping to verify that all
  scheduled open orders were shipped; and with Materials manager and purchasing to schedule outsourced or buy
  items.
- Position required compliance with ITAR regulations.

#### HR/Business Administrator, 2003 to 2005

Reported directly to the HR manager. Successfully performed HR duties and coordinated special HR/HSE/customer service projects. Assisted in the setup and training for the launch of the new computer-based open enrollment program. Established and maintained the content of the HR and HSE intranet portal sites. Organized, updated and maintained all MSDS books and database. Developed blood borne pathogen and lock-out-tag-out policy manuals. Served on the 5S team. Executed the transfer of all sales/customer service records and processes from a closing facility, maintained contact with all customers during the transition and trained new customer service employees.

- Acted as backup for HR manager as needed and performed all HR administrative functions with minimal or no supervision in a fast-paced manufacturing environment.
- Responded to inquiries from exempt and non-exempt employees on a daily basis regarding benefits, salary, payroll, leave, STD/LTD, Worker's Comp, status changes and other issues related to HR policies and procedures.
- Maintained all employee personnel files, entered new HRIS data, processed confidential reports regarding payroll, compensation, performance reviews, merit pay and bonuses and distributed payroll checks.
- Assisted with open enrollment training and offered technical help to employees regarding computer-based enrollment.
- Assisted with hiring procedures and candidate screenings: helped review new resumes/applications, scheduled interviews and pre-employment physicals/drug tests and maintained applicant tracking log.
- Prepared and processed new hire/termination paperwork, updated HRIS as required and assisted with new employee orientation.
- Liaised with staffing agencies to schedule interviews for temporary employees and once hired, provided them with timekeeping records.
- Maintained time system (Etime), PTO tracking logs and acted as liaison between employees and corporate payroll to resolve payroll issues.
- Coordinated the organization of employee events (pancake breakfast, dinner/dances, BBQ's, monthly employee meetings & a safety/health fair).
- Provided backup for Sales manager and customer service as needed.
- Traveled to other locations within our division to provide support and/or training.
- Trained new clerical hires and customer service representatives.
- Responsible for the maintenance of record retention database and files.
- Maintained and updated the wellness boards and assisted employees with information about corporate wellness programs.

## **Temporary HR Administrative Employee**, 2003

• 3 month assignment from Career Connections Staffing Services that led to a direct hire position.

# CAREER CONNECTIONS STAFFING SERVICES - Nashua, NH

#### Temporary Employee, 2000 to 2003

• Worked in various business and healthcare environments providing receptionist, secretarial, accounting assistance (account receivables and deposits), medical billing/collection services, patient intake, patient scheduling, payments, insurance benefit verification and maintenance of confidential medical files.

# WINDHAM INJURY MANAGEMENT GROUP – Manchester, NH Ergonomic Specialist I, 2003

- Participated in ergonomic evaluations associate level consulting responsibilities included fieldwork ergonomic evaluation, report writing and client follow-up.
- Managed new customer rollout and traveled to customer facilities (local & out-of-state), performed medical file
  reviews, discussed files with customer, initiated ergonomic referrals, maintained customer database and provided
  follow-up with the customer.

• Assisted senior ergonomic consultants with ergonomic training and development and helped organize/produce ergonomic power point presentations and instructional videos. Performed backup duties for Office manager.

## Administrative Staff, 2001 to 2003

- Backup for Office Manager. Assisted Office manager with account receivables, deposits, banking, producing reports, processing travel arrangements and expense reports and other miscellaneous administrative support.
- Responsible for processing all medical and consulting invoices/billing, provided training for new clerical staff and backup for receptionist.
- Assisted with reviewing resumes and scheduling applicant interviews.

#### **Work Experience**

Temporary Staffing Employee, 2000 to 2003 Seasonal Ice Cream Stand Manager, 2001 Elder Care, 1996 to 2000 Claims Support Representative, 1996 Secretary/Receptionist, 1993 to 1996

#### **Education & Professional Development**

APICS - Basics of Supply Chain Management

Chapman/Brandman University

• SHRM Essentials of Human Resource Management Certification (Included California State Laws and Regulations)

#### LinkedHR/SHRM Professional Development Series

• Understanding Key Aspects of U.S. Employment Law for 2010

Portland State University – coursework in economics and statistics (pre-requisites for Business Program)

University of Southern New Hampshire – coursework in accounting (pre-requisites for Business Program) Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI) – Introduction to Blueprint Reading

B.S. Biology Degree Equivalent from course work at the following:

- University of New Hampshire
- University of Massachusetts, Lowell

- California State University, Chico
- Fresno Community College

Completed ongoing training in employment law, benefits, worker's comp, leaves of absence, and other HR related material.